Donald Hutchison

Software Developer

Donald Hutchison

Senefelderstrasse 24A 10437 Berlin

contact@donaldhutchison.info donaldhutchison.info github.com/rkachowski

Summary

I'm a cross-skilled developer with 7+ years experience, primarily in the mobile application space. I have significant experience in mobile games application development, as well as creating the infrastructure and tooling to support them.

I enjoy creating things and new challenges, what really drives me is trying to find out if something is possible.

Experience

Wooga GmbH / SDK Engineer / Team Lead

JULY 2015 - PRESENT, BERLIN

Developing and maintaining reusable libraries for all in-house game projects. Managing live incidents and putting out fires.

- Designed custom packaging framework to enable super easy integration with game projects
- Designed and developed a cross platform Android + iOS application test framework
- Creating and maintaining Unity library projects including In App Purchases, Analytics and Tracking
- Automation of build systems and test environment
- Developed an application to manage inventory of Android devices
- Redesigned build system for internal library usage

Apportable / Software Engineer

NOVEMBER 2014 - APRIL 2015, SAN FRANCISCO

- Ensuring functionality in the interactions between projects + project versions
- Managing devops for SpriteBuilder project
- Designed CI system to work with github + pull requests for OSX application
- Implemented device agnostic resolution support

King / Games Developer

JULY 2014 - NOVEMBER 2014, BERLIN

- Developing games prototypes
- Experimenting with new UI / UX concepts
- Improving tooling to manage state flow

Wooga GmbH / Games Developer

OCTOBER 2012 - JULY 2014, BERLIN

Driving the development of Wooga's first mobile only game and

- Designed and implemented a bespoke customer support app (front + backend), saving time, effort and money in interactions with paying customers
- Rapidly prototyped several mobile game ideas
- Fully ported a successful game from iOS to Android
- Launched Jelly Splash and Pocket Village to iOS and Android platforms, each with millions of unique downloads

HuzuTech / Software Engineer

JUNE 2010 - OCTOBER 2012, GLASGOW

- Contributed to the development and release of a Flash based MMO
- Optimised existing code base and core navigation systems, resulting in a measurable UX improvement.
- Designed and implemented a content creation tool, which went on to be sold as part of the flagship product.
- Managed QA efforts and processes

Education

Glasgow Caledonian University / Bachelor of Science

AUGUST 2007 - NOVEMBER 2009, GLASGOW

Games Software Development

Skills

Programming Languages:

C, C#, Java, Objective-C, Ruby, Lua, JavaScript

Platforms:

OSX / macOS, iOS, Android, Linux, Windows